# Mateusz Witaliński

## JavaScript Developer, Team Leader



#### **PROFILE**

I am a software developer for over ten years now. My skills evolve along with the internet evolution and my great experience is growing constantly.

I have started when the Internet was making its first steps. Since then I had an opportunity to learn new technologies, be in various roles, work with new methodologies and check several different approaches. I was working with customers and developers from all around the world.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **LEOCODE** – JavaScript Developer, Team Leader & Project Manager

JUNE 2011 - PRESENT

I works on Frontend, usually with Angular, but also with pure JS/TS, React/React Native, Meteor/Express/Nest or other Node backend stack. Considered a Frontend Architect with a large expertise. Delivers a UI design as well.

Over time my competencies were expanded to include the Team Leader and the Project Manager for several projects. Demonstrates a great sense of responsibility, so can be entrusted with the biggest challenges.

### Applifactory - Self employed

OCTOBER 2009 - MAY 2011

Building various web and mobile solutions for several companies, from the small units to the biggest Polish corporations. It was the time of exploring new technologies and gaining new competences.

# **Quickfoto.pl** – Project manager, PHP and Adobe Flex Developer

JANUARY 2008 - NOVEMBER 2009

Building my own idea and vision — an advanced Photo Printing system with some extra features such as visual photo editor, calendar and photo gadget (mugs, pillows, etc.) creator.

The only technology that could deliver such a sophisticated user interface and client-side image processing those days was the Flex framework. All was wrapped up with the PHP backend.

### **CONTACT**

(+48) 600 069 909 mateusz.witalinski@gmail.com

### **WEBSITE**

https://mateusz.im/

#### **GITHUB**

@applifactory

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6

Angular, AngularJS

HTML, PUG, SLIM, HAML, CSS, STYLUS, LESS, SASS

Ionic, NativeScript

Node, Express, Nest, Meteor

React, React Native

### **METHODOLOGIES**

Scrum & Agile

### **DESIGN TOOLS**

Sketch

### **LANGUAGES**

English – Professional working proficiency

Polish - Native

# **InGenious Programmers** – Project manager, PHP and Front-end Developer

FEBRUARY 2007 - DECEMBER 2007

Building websites, CMSes, eCommerce and Rich Internet Applications using the stack far ahead of HTML and JS of those times.

# **Shanghai Doli Photographic Equipment Co., Ltd.,** China, Shanghai — Project manager, Trainee

JULY 2005 - AUGUST 2005

I was a trainee, responsible for managing a cooperation of polish and chinese software development teams, as well training the chinese staff.

## Freelance - Web Developer

JUNE 2003 - FEBRUARY 2007

Building the early internet solutions as a Frontend and Backend Developer, Designer, Copywriter and Dev-ops in one person. I have built my first commercial web app in PHP and Flash, which was a Flight Time Measurement system for a sports airports. Programming and learning.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Science and Technology (AGH), Cracow

2003 - 2009

Automatics and Robotics - Informatics in Control and Management

# School of Jazz and Contemporary Music, Cracow

2004 - 2008

Trumpet, Piano

## **PROJECTS**

# **XpressDelivery** – Team Leader, React Native Developer, Angular Developer

4 MONTHS

A platform for express products delivery based on driver's mobile app, server queue system and call center app. All parts wired up realtime.

#### **SUMMARY**

I love challenges and problem solving

I believe nothing is impossible, it is only a matter of time

I take my work very seriously and have high sense of responsibility

I have an eye for detail and pixel perfection necessity

### **ATTITUDE**

"Do. Or do not. There is no try" - Master Yoda

### AdTonos – Team Leader, Angular and Meteor Developer

6 MONTHS

Online radio advertisement targeting platform, which replaces original audio stream ads on the fly with the listener's profiled ads.

## SnapShot - Frontend Architect, Angular Developer

4 MONTHS

Multi-application hospitality data processing platform to collect, harmonize and analyze business data. I was responsible for new apps setup and architecture, frontend starter app and several platform common and framework agnostic components.

### **Decidr** – React Developer

3 MONTHS

R&D Concept app built with 100% agile methodologies on every level. Utilizes GraphQL and Amazon Cognito.

### PackChat – Team Leader, Angular and Meteor Developer

6 MONTHS

Company internal advanced chat application available for web, desktop with Electron and mobile with Ionic.

# **Performance Evaluation** — Team Leader, Angular and Meteor Developer, UI Designer

6 MONTHS

WizzAir Web based application created to gather a data from multiple internal systems and provide it in a structured visual form to reduce a time of preparation and performing evaluation meetings.

# **FeedbackTool** – Team Leader, Angular and Meteor Developer, Designer

3 MONTHS

WizzAir Web based application with strong mobile support created for daily gathering and analysing a team feedback about working with colleagues.

# **eBOS** – Frontend Developer, AngularJS Developer, Designer

4 YEARS

SlickStitch Web platform for supporting multiple processes in embroidery factory.

# **Soaply** – Team Leader, Angular Developer, Meteor Developer, Designer

6 MONTHS

Soaply Mobile app for ordering and performing car wash services on demand. Mobile app for washers, mobile app for customers, web app for both.

## RedSea – Frontend Developer, Angular Developer

10 MONTHS

SchoolBlazer Custom ERP and eCommerce platform for UK School clothing. I was responsible for refactoring old RoR views and stylesheets and building new Angular applications.

# **Promo360** – Team Leader, Frontend Developer, AngularJS Developer

4 YEARS

Dukes of London Custom webshop platform with an ability of creating and customizing customer dedicated stores.

## **LibertyVaults** – Frontend Architect

3 MONTHS

A software for storing passwords and personal data on mobile phone, accessing it via browsers. I have prepared the architecture for heuristic core available on mobile browsers and desktop browser by extensions.

### **AnyCloud** — Ionic Mobile Developer

4 MONTHS

One application to gather images, documents and other media form multiple cloud services.

## **Schoople** – AngularJS Developer, Designer

3 YEARS

SchoolOffice Web platform for selling clothing and solving multiple schools and parents cases. Responsibilities: Front-end in AngularJS and some designs.

# LuckyVoice - Adobe AIR / Flex development

2 YEARS

LuckyVoice is a Karaoke platform. My role was to develop and support the karaoke club application.